suppose A and B are two positive real
numbers draw a right isoceles triangle
with side length sare otk of a so that
its area is/ 12 * a off the top vertex
draw a right isoceles triangle with s
side length square root B so that it has
an area of 1 12 B these two triangles
form the boundary of a rectangle that
has Dimensions squ < TK of a and squ <
TK of B so it has an area of the squ <
TK of a * B in this diagram imagine
folds along the top and left of the
rectangle so that when we fold in the
two isoc right triangles they meet along
their diagonal like this because the
areas of the two triangles cover the
area of the rectangle we see that the
square root of a * B which is the area
of the rectangle is less than or equal
to 12 a + 1 12 B this inequality is
known as the arithmetic mean geometric
mean inequality note that we get
equality if and only if the Shaded area
is a square so that A and B are equal